这个，它让我知道：
2个
许多世界被奴役
由野兽和他的军队，屠夫。
3个
这也让我知道：
4个
野兽会来到我们的世界，
克鲁尔的世界……
5个
他的黑色堡垒会被看到
在这片土地上...
6个
燃烧村庄的烟雾
会使天空变暗...
垂死者的哭声回荡
穿过荒凉的山谷。
8个
但有一件事我不知道：
预言是否真实...
那位古名少女
将成为女王……
她将选择一位国王，然后
他们将一起统治我们的世界......
还有他们的儿子
将统治银河系。
父亲！
科尔温现在应该已经到了。
他可能被迫旅行
穿过森林和石头国家。
所有的通行证和道路
由 Slayers 持有。
科尔温可能无法通过。
那会让你高兴吗？
我派人去帮忙。
但我看不出结盟的理由
与我们古老的敌人。
侵略者之父
正在摧毁我们的世界。
我们必须有联盟。
只要我们团结，
我们有机会对抗他们吗？
那么，我将与图罗德国王缔结条约。
没有必要
你嫁给他的儿子。
这是唯一的方法
保证联盟。
婚姻是我的选择。
如果不是 Turold 的儿子的话。
科尔温是一名伟大的战士。
好战士会成为坏丈夫。
也许。
骑兵逼近！
打开大门！
我们已发送给您寻求帮助。没有人来。
二十个人被派往你那里。
我们已经失去了 300 到这里。
这场婚姻不是我选择的，图罗德。
我也没有，Eirig。
我选择了它！你的女儿选择了它。
会完成的。
你将和我一起领导这支军队
对抗屠夫？
无论我有什么军队，
我会带头对抗他们...
直到我赢了或者我死了。
我选择的很好。
我也有。
你的旅程很艰难吗？
但是必要的。
- 可能已经太晚了。
- 不算太晚。
48岁
这是举行仪式的地方吗？
今晚月出。
我父亲说好战士
做坏丈夫。
- 那要看。
- 什么？
关于你是否期待丈夫
跟着你……
每次拍手都要跳。
你不为我跳吗？
不，当然不是。你是个战士。
从今天起，我的王国不再存在。
也不是我的。
我们的孩子统治下的单一王国。
同意。
我给水火。
它不会回来，除了从手中
我选择的女人作为我的妻子。
我取水火。
我只给男人
我选择谁作为我的丈夫。
从我手中拿走火。
点名，卫兵！
- 杀手！
- 武装自己！
- 我们会一起战斗。
- 没有。有安全的出路吗？
- 地下通道。
- 快点！
我的位置是和你在一起。
- 你爱我吗？
- 我当然爱你。
然后去。
科尔温，快点回到我身边。
房间中央的每个人，
回来！
拿着！
这里！
科尔温！
丽莎！
父亲！
她还活着。
在哪里？
别动！
现在，超出你的范围。
你是谁？
我是伊尼尔。
旧的。
90后
好吧，没有那么老。
你下来了
来自花岗岩山脉。
是的。现在需要我。
父亲！
现在没有时间悲伤。
你没有失去父亲
和新娘在同一天。
那天我也没有成为国王。
我没有王国。
你的王国可能更大
比你知道的。
我把它给你，老人，
欢迎来到它。
我是来找国王的...
我找到了一个男孩。
丽莎？
他们会把她关在黑堡垒里。
你能带我去吗？
你一定有帮助。
我会在路上找到男人。
在堡垒里，
你将面对的不仅仅是杀手。
你将面对野兽，
谁是他们的领袖。
他可以被杀死。
也许。
但没有人见过他并活下来。
你需要的不仅仅是人和剑。
您将需要战刃的力量。
战刃什么都不是
而是一个古老的符号。
它并不真正存在。
它存在，在那里。
最高峰的一处山洞内。
没有战刃，
你永远无法到达Lyssa。
我需要武器，而不是符号。
曾经，战刃是
一种非常强大的武器。
它可以再次如此。
但只有在合适的人的手中。
只为对的人
可以取回战刃。
我是那个男人吗？
我希望我知道。
我不能和你一起去。
不用担心。如果它在那里，
我会回来的。
如果你不带着它回来...
你根本不会回来。
你被带到这里是为了结婚。
我是你会选择的国王。
除非你需要它，否则不要使用它。
- 我怎么知道什么时候？
- 你会知道的。
如果你带我去黑堡垒，
我会尽快使用它。
那可没那么容易。
每次日出时，黑色堡垒都会移动。
有时在山上，
有时在沙漠...
“有时在海里。”
从来没有同一个地方两次。
但是你告诉我你知道在哪里可以找到它！
有王者之德
除了勇敢。
礼貌就是其中之一。
对不起。
那是莱莎的想法。
我也是，小时候...
一次。
我也像你一样爱过。
但你的爱会...
比我幸运。
我告诉你的是我知道
怎么找到堡垒...
那就是寻求异象
盲人翡翠先知。
但他的位置也不为人知。
我知道。
从这里出发需要一天的路程。来。
帮助！
帮助！我快淹死了！
这可能是流沙！
我可能已经被吸死了
当你站在那里发呆时！
这个地方在哪？
花岗岩山脉附近的森林。
爆破！偏离航线 1,000 英里。
我很着急。
有意见分歧
关于醋栗派。
那人把它留在他的窗台上。
- 他期望什么？
- 也许他想吃掉它。
对于那种粗鲁，笨蛋，
我想我会把你变成一只蝙蝠。
可能会教你一些礼仪
倒挂一两个小时。
山民缺乏造成伤害的力量。
我们会看到的，老人。
我们会看到的！
不，那是热软糖酱的配方。
它必须是一只鹅。
又胖又丑。
很胖。非常难看。
从那，你知道我能做些什么
如果我是一个报复心重的人。
你现在可以离开我了。
亲爱的，亲爱的。现在让我看看...
森林并不安全。
你最好和我们一起旅行！
我，陪你去旅行？
你知道我是谁吗？
不。
我是伟大的埃尔戈。
个子矮，力气大。。。
目标狭窄，视野开阔。
而且我不和农民一起旅行
和乞丐。再见。
等待！等等我！
我刚想起来
我有这方面的紧急任务。
什么生意？
活着。
我会让你走
在这些墙内的任何地方。
因为这是你的宫殿
将统治这个世界和无数其他人。
你逃不过我。
你将成为我的女王。
老头子，你不太会选路。
这样可以节省我们半天的路程。
强盗。
他们是男人，我们还不知道
他们是否是强盗。
脸那么丑
只能属于强盗。
不用担心。我要把他们都变成猪。
你被100个人包围了！
100个不够！
我们这里有什么？斗士！
此外，你还缺少大约 90 个人。
让我们杀死他们并完成它。
温柔，鲁恩！我不杀人
没有充分的理由。
我也没有。为此心存感激。
你是逃犯。
每个人。奴隶、强盗、
战士和争吵者。
绝望的男人。
- 就像你所看到的一样绝望。
- 好的。
那些是我需要的人。
你需要？
好吧，看，这些人
除了我，别跟着任何人……
我根本不跟随任何人。
- 你会跟随国王吗？
- 国王？
有很多疯子在游荡
自称是国王的国家。
你会跟随国王吗
去黑堡垒？
现在我知道你是个疯子。
我不会跟随我自己的父亲
到黑堡垒。
- 如果他能找到的话！
——他不会那么傻。
捍卫你的世界是愚蠢的吗？
为你的家园和家人而战？
如果侵略者征服，
你将成为我们其他人的奴隶。
高尚的情操，但我们为利益而战。
- 你知道我的意思？
- 利润的自由。和名气。
自由？但我们有。
和名望，它是一个空钱包。
算了吧，破产了……
吃吧，饿了……
寻找它然后发疯。
那是真实的。
但这种名声和这种自由
你可以留给你的儿子。
你怎么知道我有儿子的？
如果屠夫征服了克鲁尔，
你的儿子将永远被奴役。
我没有儿子，但我会和你一起去。
这个男孩让你们都感到羞耻。
只有国王和元帅
有这些手铐的钥匙。
- 你看起来不像元帅。
- 不。
你看起来适龄
成为图罗德的儿子。
确切的年龄。
Torquil，你变老了。
你的大脑软化了。
像你这样的九个人抵得上一支军队。
如果我们成功了，解锁它们。
否则，我会和他们一起死。
好吧，你听到他了！我们现在是军队！
一支没有报酬的军队。
你有问题吗，鲁恩？
一个人甚至不能自言自语
不被打扰？
我们走吧！
- 一起来！
- 能诺格！移动！
醋栗！
因此！
伊尼尔，救命！
可怕！有
那边有个可怕的生物。
而那边，
只有一只眼睛的生物。
一只眼睛？ '一个独眼巨人。
他正把长矛对准我。
如果是这样，你现在已经死了。
他的目标是杀手……
因为他们有着古老的仇恨
它们之间。
很久以前，他的祖先住
在远离克鲁尔的世界。
并且有...
两只眼睛和其他男人一样。
然后他们和野兽做了一笔交易
谁是杀戮者的领袖。
他们放弃了一只眼睛
以换取力量……
展望未来。
但是他们被骗了。
为了唯一的未来
他们被允许看到...
是他们自己死亡的时间。
他们是悲伤的、孤独的生物，
生来就知道...
他们死去的那一天。
今天本来是我的一天，
如果不是他的话。
上你去
我们三个继续。
其余的将留在这里。
我们四个继续。我不会留下
与这些罪犯！
我们四个人去。
他带领我们
朝向坚硬的岩石表面。
这个人的脑壳里有葡萄干。
我认识一个老朋友。
疯狂的。他们都疯了！
我们寻找黑色堡垒。
这样的愿景会遭到反对。
谁寻求它？
新国王。
用苍老的声音？
你知道那个声音吗？
是的我的朋友。
我们正在努力寻找...
我会为你寻找堡垒。
- 有糖球吗？
- 不。
- Gumdrops？
你是个什么样的男孩？
男孩子总是有糖果。
我有一个肉桂棒。
分享和分享。
我是伟大的埃尔戈。
个子矮，力气大，
目标狭窄，视野开阔。
这是非常令人印象深刻的。
我希望如此。
我是蒂奇。
这并不令人印象深刻，但足够了。
黑色要塞。
它在哪里？
你没事儿吧？
是的。
野兽不喜欢
好奇的先知窥探他的事务。
他的力量太大了
为你克服？
是的。这里。但是有一个地方
他的力量无法到达的地方。
翡翠寺。
是的。在那个地方，
他不能反对我的愿景。
你会和我们一起去那里旅行吗？
它在大沼泽中：
险恶之地。
我们的需要很大。
神庙位于沼泽的中心，
三棵树长成一棵。
那个地方怎么能长出什么东西来？
它闻起来有死亡的味道。
死亡和权力是近亲。
老头子，别以为我喜欢你的亲戚。
看一看。
此行之利。
他们值一大笔钱。
或许。给某人
谁非常近视。
什么？
但它们是祖母绿。
嘿，鲁恩，祖母绿。
我发誓！它们是祖母绿！
我们口袋里的石头和墓碑
在我们头顶之上就是我们将从中得到的一切。
杀手！
- 来自湖边！
- 掩护！
- 在这里！
- 下来。
下去吧！
快，那边！
科尔温！
在这里！
这是第二次
你救了我的命。
- 我是尔格。
- 壮丽的。
他没有名字吗？
他的名字叫雷尔。
他有时会拜访先知。
他话不多。
所以我注意到了。除了讽刺
给希望成为朋友的人。
或者和那些人开玩笑
谁已经是他的朋友了。
我的名字不是开玩笑，豆杆。很高兴
如果你有 20 英尺高，请起个短名字...
但小人物需要大名字
给他们重量。
我的朋友，你的行为会给你带来重量。
我看到你从矛中救了那个男孩。
这才是朋友该有的样子
为彼此做。
这么。
你已经和我们在一起很长一段时间了。
从一开始。当我学会
那个老头已经下来了……
我知道时机已到。
那就加入我们吧。所有男人都需要陪伴。
是的。
所有人。
那样。
如果我有我的愿望，
我会马上离开这个阴暗的地方。
如果我真的如愿以偿，我会
坐在醋栗派上……
大如山。
不，这有点贪心。
我会满足于一个像房子一样大的。
我想要一只小狗。
只有一只小狗？如果你愿意，
为什么不希望 100.7
我只想要一个。
这是一个愚蠢的愿望。
而你，瑞尔，你想要什么？
无知。
不！
.Nennog！
- 帮助！
帮助他！
地面。它正在下沉！
这是野兽的力量。
- 衔接！做链条！
- 帮助！放我出去！
鲁恩，抓住他！
匆忙！
- 不挂断！
- 拉！
给我斧头！
这里！
拉！
我滑倒了！
拉它！
门诺！
帮我！
放我出去！帮我！
门诺！保持静止！不要挣扎！
坚持，稍等！
抵达！
别动，门诺！
不要挣扎！
拉！
门诺！
是你吗，蒂奇？
- 到圣殿有多远？
- 现在不远了。
留在这里，确保
我们没有被跟踪。
- 我会留下来。
- 当心。
谢谢你。
我会带领先知。蒂奇，你继续。
谢谢你，兄弟。
我会带领先知。你
继续Titch。
- 这边走？
- 不。
你确定？
我认得这棵树。
我现在认得那个地方了。
我们看到树了，兄弟。
寻求知识的人
必须带领我。
其他人不得靠近。
这是您寻求的知识。
野兽有很多武器。
这是其中之一。
换生灵。
你怎么知道？
我在流沙中找到了先知的尸体。
他为我们献出了生命。
他是我唯一的家人。
我们现在是你的家人。
现在我们没有办法
找到黑色堡垒。
有人可能会提供帮助。
谁？
网络寡妇。
那个生物帮不了任何人。
去那里的人都没有回来。
- 她有强大的力量。
- 是的，杀人。
她可能不会杀我，因为我知道她的名字。
她的名字叫死神。
她曾经有过另一个名字。
一个古老而强大的名字。
在这段旅程中，我们都冒着生命危险。
我的风险并不比你大。
我必须试试。
我的论文在哪里？
爆炸，我真的必须组织起来
这些日子中的一天。
小狗！
尔格在哪里？
他很快就会回来。
从这里开始，我独自前行。
- 我和你一起去。
- 不。
如果两个方法，
她肯定会杀了他们。
一个人，我可能还有机会。
每个人都有自己的命运，科尔温。
是的。
是的，每个人都有自己的命运。
如果我早上还没回来...
你会知道我的。
我们留在这里。
我仍然说这是一个愚蠢的愿望。
我们没有食物，
男人们太累了，无法打猎。
- 嘿，基根。
- 你好。
不是你的一个妻子吗
住在这附近的村子里？
洛娜。不，她搬到了河边。
他有几个老婆？
最后一数，大概有七八个人。
你看，他是个旅行家。
他涵盖了很多领域。
优点。
她住在一个村庄
在巨树的边缘。
她会做饭吗？
这不是她的强项，
但是听着，我告诉你。
只要让她带上食物就行了。
宏伟估计他会做饭。
我们很快就会看到。
如果你还饿的话还有很多。
别挡我的路。让我开始吧。
- 出色地？
- 嗯，什么？
那女孩是谁？
她的村庄被烧毁了。
她无处可去，所以我收留了她。
再看她一眼，
我会把她扔出去！
值得！哦，我的宝贝。
她对你不屑一顾。
- 她甚至都不漂亮。
- 是的？
现在，看，花瓣，
“忠实”是我的中间名。
你必须吃点东西。
我不饿。
请为我
谢谢你。
你有什么烦恼？
你选择了一个微不足道的王国
在一个微不足道的星球上。
和爱。
爱情转瞬即逝。
力量是永恒的。
这就是我的力量。
它可以是你的。
我不要你的力量。
不要让我的形式吓到你。
丽莎。
我可以采取任何我想要的形式。
任何你想要的形式。
没有那种形式的爱。
你认为有爱
在你的男孩国王？
我没有把男人抱在怀里
自从爱人离开。
这是个谎言！
我知道这有多痛苦
远离你的爱人。
他会背叛你。
安慰我一晚。
他不会。
我不能背叛我的新娘。
然后他会死。
让我安慰你。
当她没有时，我无法接受安慰。
那你不会吗？
我不能。
我师傅说：
“让他背叛她，否则，杀了他。”
是的，他是我的主人。这些爪子
离你的喉咙只有一个心跳。
我本可以立刻杀了你。
但是，在我认识你的那一刻，我爱上了你。
背叛的是你。
权力转瞬即逝。
爱是永恒的。
记住账号。
考虑一下这种力量。
如果你同意做我的女王...
我会阻止屠夫的攻击。
这是在你的权力
停止杀戮和燃烧。
你每耽误一个小时，
更多无辜的人将被杀害。
考虑一下。
快点，科尔温。
我要找寡妇！
进入这里然后死去。
丽莎！
谁说出这个名字？
是我，茵尼尔！
这次我给你。
丽莎。
当我最后一次听到这个名字时，我还很年轻。
上次跟你说这话的时候我还很年轻。
我的脸和我的名字一样美丽。
我全心全意地爱着你，丽莎。
但你不会留在我身边。
- 有责任，职责......
- 野心。
你有一个儿子。
我们有一个儿子。
但你什么也没说。
他在哪里？
他一出生我就杀了他。
而这就是我的惩罚。
我的儿子？
既然杀不了你，
我的愤怒需要一个牺牲品。
我知道你永远无法原谅我。
我无法原谅自己。
我已经原谅你了。
你永远不能原谅一个女人
谁杀了你的儿子。
如果我没有...
我现在能像当时看到你那样看到你吗？
并让我看透你的眼睛。
我怎么可能离开你？
你的远见是你给我的礼物。
你的远见可能是你给我的礼物。
- 我能为你看什么？
- 黑色堡垒，它从哪里升起？
明天...
在钢铁沙漠。
但知识无用，
因为你不能离开这里。
没有人能逃脱网络。
有一个年轻的女孩被关押
在堡垒中。
一个叫你名字的年轻女孩。
一个年轻人在找她。
我当时的年纪...
你我相遇。
当你我相爱。
你的要求超出了我的能力范围。
它只能转动一次。
这就是网络法则。
那么第二个莱莎将分享你的命运。
她会死去，变老和孤独。
她将死在黑暗的地方。
这个世界将是一个黑暗的地方。
这些是我生命中的沙子。
接受他们和蜘蛛
将无力伤害您。
但是你自己的生命会随着沙子耗尽。
你的生活如何？
我把它给了以我的名字命名的女孩。
我无法阻止沙子。
你不能停止时间。
现在出发。
拯救另一个丽莎。
日出时...
黑色堡垒将出现...
在钢铁沙漠。
它将留在那里直到日出
第二天。
你必须...
你必须达到它。
我们会达到的。你会和我们在一起。
不。
不，我的...
比赛开始了。
明智地使用你的力量。
不要浪费它。
我从你那里学到了力量。
我不会忘记的。
我们会把他埋在这里。
铁沙漠距离这里 1,000 里格。
火母马。
火母马可以旅行
一天 1,000 里格。
如果我们行动迅速，还有时间。
就是这样。赶他们回去！
灰色是领导者！
抓住他！
快点！快点！
我有你。
温柔如婴儿！
- 快给其他人装鞍！
- 正确的！
快点。静止不动！
站住，你这个野兽！
好好照顾他。
- 他为什么不来？
- 他该死了。
如果他无论如何都要死，
他为什么不和我们一起去？
不行，他必须留在这里认命。
如果他反对，
他会给自己带来巨大的痛苦。
稳定的！我必须留在这里。
是时候了吗？
你已经做得够多了，瑞尔。留在这儿。
每个人都有自己的命运。
雷尔，我会和你一起骑。
我必须留在这里，我的朋友。
我们没有时间。
坚持，稍等！
在那里！
是的，只有疯子才会想要
接近它。
我们会更接近。
而且很快。天快亮了。
我们必须进去
在双胞胎太阳升起之前。
润，回来！
我错了。
这次旅行是值得的。
完成它...
- 我们得赶他们走。
- 不，等等！
我们一搬家就会被接走。
科尔温，看。
跟着他！
快点！
凯根！小心男孩！
让你的斧头开场！
这是没有用的。
这是我的时间。
继续移动！
哪一条路？
当心！
- 我旅行的日子结束了，我的朋友。
- 我们会带你离开这里。
这是我住的地方。
领先。
我抱不住他！
给我们一根绳子！
杀手！
我要下去。
去！
回来！
- 出来！
- 不，等等！
我们无能为力。出去！
从这里开始，我必须独自前行。
去哪里？没有办法进去。
有一种方法。
我们必须找到其他人，埃尔戈。
他们已经停止了。
巴道夫，放手！
当心！
'丽莎！ .Colwyn！
不在这里，科尔温。他太厉害了。
你必须在远离中心的地方与他作战。
战刃不见了。
我没有办法和他战斗。
科尔温，不是战刃，是你。
不，莱莎，是我们。
是我们他打不过。
它不会回到我身边，除非从手中
我选择的女人作为我的妻子。
我只给男人
我选择谁作为我的丈夫。
从我手中拿走火。
我们必须找到其他人。快点！
我不会离开你的，尔格。
- 巴道夫？
- 看，这边！
那是尔格。他可能还活着。
我们离开这里吧。
他冒着生命危险来拯救我们。
我们不能把他留在这里
如果他还有机会活着的话。
来吧，让我们带你离开这里。
退后！
扶他们下来！
他会没事的。
- 你是他的王后？
- 是的。
- 那么我们赢了。
好家伙！我应该坚持小狗！
我认为...
是时候解开那些手铐了。
我以为我会保留它们
作为我们旅途的纪念。
钥匙是你的。
只有国王和他的元帅大人
携带这把钥匙。
这是正确的。
一个古名的女孩将成为女王。
她将选择一位国王，
他们将共同统治我们的世界……
他们的儿子将统治银河系。
This, it was given me to know:
That many worlds have been enslaved
by the Beast and his army, the Slayers.
And this, too, was given me to know:
That the Beast would come to our world,
the world of Krull...
and his Black Fortress would be seen
in the land...
that the smoke of burning villages
would darken the sky...
and the cries of the dying echo
through deserted valleys.
But one thing I cannot know:
Whether the prophecy be true...
that a girl of ancient name
shall become queen...
that she shall choose a king, and that
together they shall rule our world...
and that their son
shall rule the galaxy.
Father!
Colwyn should have been here by now.
He may be forced to travel
through the forests and the stone country.
All the passes and the roads
are held by the Slayers.
Colwyn may not get through.
That would please you?
I sent men to help.
But I see no reason for an alliance
with our ancient enemies.
Father, the invaders
are destroying our world.
We must have the alliance.
Only if we're united,
do we stand a chance against them.
Then, I'll make a treaty with King Turold.
It's not necessary for
you to marry his son.
It's the only way to
guarantee the alliance.
The marriage is my choice.
If it were anyone but Turold's son.
Colwyn is a great fighter.
Good fighters make bad husbands.
Perhaps.
Horsemen approaching!
Open the gate!
We sent to you for help. None came.
Twenty men were despatched to you.
We've lost 300 getting here.
I didn't choose this marriage, Turold.
Nor did I, Eirig.
I chose it! Your daughter chose it.
It'll be done.
And you'll lead this army with mine
against the Slayers?
Whatever army I have,
I'll lead against them...
until I've won or I'm dead.
I have chosen well.
So have I.
Your journey was hard?
But necessary.
- It may already be too late.
- It's not too late.
Is this where the ceremony will be?
Tonight at moonrise.
My father says that good fighters
make bad husbands.
- That depends.
- On what?
On whether you expect a husband
to follow you around...
jump every time you clap your hands.
Wouldn't you jump for me?
No, of course not. You're a warrior.
From this day, my kingdom is no more.
Nor mine.
A single kingdom under our children.
Agreed.
I give fire to water.
It will not return, except from the hand
of the woman I choose as my wife.
I take fire from water.
I give it only to the man
whom I choose as my husband.
Take the fire from my hand.
Call the roll, guards!
- Slayers!
- Arm yourselves!
- We'll fight together.
- No. Is there a safe way out?
- An underground passage.
- Come on!
My place is with you.
- Do you love me?
- Of course I love you.
Then go.
Colwyn, hurry back to me.
Everyone in the centre of the room,
get back!
Take it!
Here!
Colwyn!
Lyssa!
Father!
She's alive.
Where?
Stay still!
For now, beyond your reach.
Who are you?
I am Ynyr.
The old one.
Well, not as old as all that.
You've come down
from the Granite Mountains.
Yes. I am needed now.
Father!
There's no time now for grief.
You haven't lost a father
and a bride on the same day.
Nor have I become king on that day.
I have no kingdom.
Your kingdom may be greater
than you know.
I give it to you, old man,
and welcome to it.
I came to find a king...
and I find a boy instead.
Lyssa?
They will hold her in the Black Fortress.
Can you lead me to it?
You must have help.
I'll find men on the way.
In the Fortress,
you will face more than the Slayers.
You will face the Beast,
who is their leader.
He can be killed.
Perhaps.
But no man has ever seen him and lived.
You will need more than men and swords.
You will need the power of the Glaive.
The Glaive is nothing
but an ancient symbol.
It doesn't really exist.
It exists, up there.
In a cave on the highest peak.
Without the Glaive,
you will never be able to reach Lyssa.
I need weapons, not symbols.
Once, the Glaive was
a very powerful weapon.
It can be so again.
But only in the hands of the right man.
For only the right man
can retrieve the Glaive.
Am I that man?
I wish I knew.
I cannot go with you.
Don't worry. If it's there,
I'll come back with it.
If you do not come back with it...
you'll not come back at all.
You have been brought here for a marriage.
I am the king you will choose.
Do not use it until you need it.
- How will I know when?
- You'll know.
If you lead me to the Black Fortress,
I'll use it soon enough.
That will not be so easy.
At each sunrise, the Black Fortress moves.
Sometimes it is in the mountains,
sometimes in the desert...
"sometimes in the sea."
Never the same place twice.
But you told me you knew where to find it!
There are kingly virtues
other than bravery.
Courtesy is one of them.
I'm sorry.
It's the thought of Lyssa there.
I, too, was young...
once.
I, too, loved as you do.
But your love will be...
luckier than mine.
What I told you is that I knew
how to find the Fortress...
and that is by seeking the vision
of the blind Emerald Seer.
But his place isn't known either.
It is known to me.
It is a day's journey from here. Come.
Help!
Help! I'm drowning!
This might have been quicksand!
I might have been sucked to my death
while you stood there gawking!
Where is this place?
The forest near the Granite Mountains.
Blast! 1,000 miles off course.
I was rushed.
There was a difference of opinion
concerning a gooseberry pie.
The man left it sitting on his windowsill.
- What did he expect?
- Perhaps he expected to eat it.
For that rudeness, lout,
I think I'll turn you into a bat.
Might teach you some manners
to hang upside down for an hour or two.
The Hill People lack the power to do harm.
We shall see about that, old man.
We'll see about that!
No, that's a recipe for hot fudge sauce.
It'll have to be a goose.
Fat and ugly.
Very fat. Very ugly.
From that, you see what I could've done
to you if I were a vengeful man.
You may leave me now.
Dear, dear. Let me see now...
The forest is not safe.
You'd best travel with us!
Me, travel with you?
Do you know who I am?
No.
I am Ergo the Magnificent.
Short in stature, tall in power...
narrow of purpose and wide of vision.
And I do not travel with peasants
and beggars. Goodbye.
Wait! Wait for me!
I've just remembered
I have urgent business in this direction.
What business?
Staying alive.
I will allow you to go
wherever you please within these walls.
For this is the palace from which you
will rule this world and countless others.
You cannot escape me.
You will be my queen.
You're no great chooser of roads, old man.
This way will save us half a day's travel.
Robbers.
They're men, we don't know yet
whether they're robbers.
Faces that ugly
could only belong to robbers.
Don't worry. I'll turn them all into pigs.
You're surrounded by 100 men!
100 is not enough!
What have we here? A fighter!
Besides, you're short about 90 men.
Let's just kill them and be done with it.
Soft, Rhun! I don't kill men
without good reason.
Nor do I. And be thankful for it.
You're escaped prisoners.
Every one. Slaves, bandits,
fighters and brawlers.
Desperate men.
- As desperate as you'll ever see.
- Good.
Those are the kind of men I need.
You need?
Well, see, these men
follow no man but me...
and I follow no man at all.
- Would you follow a king?
- A king?
There are many lunatics wandering
through the country claiming to be kings.
Would you follow a king
to the Black Fortress?
Now I know you're a lunatic.
I wouldn't follow my own father
to the Black Fortress.
- If he could find it!
- He wouldn't be so foolish.
Is it foolish to defend your world?
To fight for your homes and families?
If the invaders conquer,
you'll be slaves with the rest of us.
Noble sentiments, but we fight for profit.
- You know what I mean?
- The profit's freedom. And fame.
Freedom? But we have it.
And fame, it's an empty purse.
Count it, go broke...
eat it, go hungry...
seek it and go mad.
That is true.
But this fame and this freedom
you could leave to your sons.
How did you know I had sons?
If the Slayers conquer Krull,
your sons will be enslaved forever.
I have no sons, but I will go with you.
The boy shames you all.
Only the king and the lord marshal
have the keys to these manacles.
- You don't look like a lord marshal.
- No.
You look about the right age
to be Turold's son.
The exact age.
Torquil, you're growing old.
Your brain's softening.
Nine men like you are worth an army.
If we succeed, unlock them.
Otherwise, I'll die with them.
Well, you heard him! We're now an army!
An unpaid army.
You got a problem, Rhun?
Can't a man even talk to himself
without being interrupted?
Let's go!
- Come along!
- Nennog! Move!
Gooseberries!
Ergo!
Ynyr, help!
Horrible! There was
a terrible creature over there.
And over there,
a creature with only one eye.
One eye? 'A cyclops.
He was aiming a spear straight at me.
Had it been so, you would now be dead.
He was aiming at a Slayer...
for they have ancient hatred
between them.
Long ago, his ancestors lived
in a world far from Krull.
And had...
two eyes like other men.
Then they made a bargain with the Beast
who is the leader of the Slayers.
They gave up one of their eyes
in exchange for the power...
to see into the future.
But they were cheated.
For the only future
they are permitted to see...
is the time of their own death.
They're sad, solitary creatures,
born to know...
the day they will die.
Today would have been my day,
if it hadn't been for him.
Up you go
We three will go on.
The rest will remain here.
We four will go on. I'm not staying behind
with these criminals!
We four will go.
He marches us
towards a solid face of rock.
The man has raisins in his braincase.
I recognise an old friend.
Mad. They're all mad!
We seek the Black Fortress.
Such a vision will be opposed.
Who seeks it?
The new king.
With an old voice?
You know the voice?
Yes, my friend.
We're trying to find the...
I will seek the Fortress for you.
- Got any sugarballs?
- No.
- Gumdrops?
What kind of boy are you?
Boys always have candy.
I have a cinnamon bar.
Share and share alike.
I am Ergo the Magnificent.
Short in stature, tall in power,
narrow of purpose and wide of vision.
That is very impressive.
I should hope so.
I'm Titch.
That's not impressive, but adequate.
The Black Fortress.
Where is it?
Are you all right?
Yes.
The Beast does not like
curious Seers poking into his affairs.
His power is too great
for you to overcome?
Yes. Here. But there is one place
where his power cannot reach.
The Emerald Temple.
Yes. In that place,
he cannot oppose my vision.
Will you travel there with us?
It is in the Great Swamp:
A treacherous place.
Our need is great.
The Temple is at the centre of the Swamp,
where three trees grow as one.
How can anything grow in that place?
It smells of death.
Death and power are close cousins.
Don't think I like your relatives, old man.
Have a look.
The profit of this journey.
They're worth a fortune.
Maybe. To someone
who's very nearsighted.
What?
But they were emeralds.
Hey, Rhun, emeralds.
I swear it! They were emeralds!
Rocks in our pockets and gravestones
above our heads is all we'll get from this.
Slayers!
- From the lake!
- Take cover!
- Over here!
- Get down.
Get down there!
Quick, over there!
Colwyn!
Over here!
That's the second time
you've saved my life.
- I am Ergo.
- The Magnificent.
Hasn't he got a name?
His name is Rell.
He visits the Seer sometimes.
He doesn't speak much.
So I've noticed. Except to be sarcastic
to people who wish to be friends.
Or jest with those
who already are his friends.
My name is no jest, beanpole. It's nice to
have a short name if you're 20 feet tall...
but small people need large names
to give them weight.
Your actions give you weight, my friend.
I saw you save the boy from a spear.
That's what friends are supposed
to do for each other.
Quite so.
You've been with us for a long way now.
Since the beginning. When I learned
that the Old One had come down...
I knew that the time had come.
Join us, then. All men need company.
Yes.
All men.
That way.
If I had my wish,
I'd be out of this gloomy place right away.
If I really had my wish, I'd be
sitting on top of a gooseberry pie...
as big as a mountain.
No, that's a bit greedy.
I'll settle for one as big as a house.
I'd wish for a puppy.
Only one puppy? If you're wishing,
why not wish for 100.7
I only want one.
That's a foolish wish.
And you, Rell, what would you wish for?
Ignorance.
No!
.Nennog!
- Help!
Help him!
The ground. It's sinking!
It is the power of the Beast.
- Link up! Make a chain!
- Help! Get me out!
Rhun, get hold of him!
Hurry!
- Hang on!
- Pull!
Give me the axe!
Here!
Pull!
I'm slipping!
Pull it!
Menno!
Help me!
Get me out! Help me!
Menno! Keep still! Don't struggle!
Hold on!
Reach!
Keep still, Menno!
Don't struggle!
Pull!
Menno!
Is that you, Titch?
- How far to the Temple?
- Not far now.
Stay here, make sure
we're not being followed.
- I will stay.
- Be careful.
Thank you.
I'll lead the Seer. Titch, you go ahead.
Thank you, brother.
I'll lead the Seer. You
go ahead with Titch.
- This way?
- No.
You sure?
I recognise this tree.
I recognise the place now.
We're in sight of the trees, brother.
He who seeks the knowledge
must lead me.
No one else may approach.
Here is the knowledge you seek.
The Beast has many weapons.
This was one of them.
The Changeling.
How did you know?
I found the Seer's body in the quicksand.
He gave his life for us.
He was my only family.
We're your family now.
Now we have no way
to find the Black Fortress.
There is one who might help.
Who?
The Widow of the Web.
That creature helps no one.
And none who go there return.
- She has great powers.
- Yeah, to kill.
She may not kill me, for I know her name.
Her name is Death.
She had another name once.
An ancient and powerful name.
We all risk our lives on this journey.
My risk is no greater than yours.
I must try.
Where are my papers?
Blast, I really must get organised
one of these days.
Puppy!
Where's Ergo?
He'll be back soon.
From here, I go on alone.
- I'm going with you.
- No.
If two approach,
she would certainly kill both.
Alone, I may have a chance.
Each to his fate, Colwyn.
Yeah.
Yes, each to his fate.
If I'm not back by morning...
you'll know mine.
We stay here.
I still say it was a foolish wish.
We have no food,
and the men are too tired to hunt.
- Hey, Kegan.
- Hello.
Doesn't one of your wives
live in a village near here?
Lona. No, she moved down to the river.
How many wives does he have?
About seven or eight, at the last count.
He's a travelling man, you see.
He covers a lot of ground.
Merith.
She lives in a village
at the edge of the giant trees.
Can she cook?
It's not her strongest point,
but hear, I tell you.
Just have her bring provisions.
Magnificence there reckons he can cook.
We'll soon see.
Plenty more if you're still hungry.
Out of my way. Let me get at it.
- Well?
- Well, what?
Who's the girl then?
Her village was burned.
She'd nowhere to go, so I took her in.
Look at her one more time,
and I'll throw her out!
Merith! Oh, my sweet.
She doesn't hold a candle to you.
- She's not even pretty.
- Yeah?
Now, look, petal,
"faithful" is my middle name.
You must eat something.
I'm not hungry.
Please, for me.
Thank you.
What troubles you?
You have chosen a paltry kingdom
on an insignificant planet.
And love.
Love is ﬂeeting.
Power is eternal.
Such is my power.
It can be yours.
I don't want your power.
Do not let my form frighten you.
Lyssa.
I can assume any form I wish.
Any form you wish.
There's no love in that form.
And you think there's love
in your boy king?
I've not held a man in my arms
since my lover left.
This is a lie!
I know how painful it is
to be far from your lover.
He will betray you.
Comfort me for one night.
He will not.
I can't betray my bride.
Then he will die.
Let me comfort you.
I can't accept comfort when she has none.
You will not then?
I cannot.
My master said:
"Make him betray her. If not, kill him."
Yes, he is my master. These talons
were a heartbeat away from your throat.
I could have killed you in an instant.
But, in the hour I knew you, I loved you.
It is you who are betrayed.
Power is fleeting.
Love is eternal.
Remember me.
Consider this power.
If you consent to be my queen...
I will halt the attacks of the Slayers.
It is in your power
to stop the killing and burning.
Each hour you delay,
more innocent people will be killed.
Think on it.
Hurry, Colwyn.
I seek the Widow!
Enter here and die.
Lyssa!
Who speaks that name?
It is I, Ynyr!
I give you this time.
Lyssa.
I was young when I last heard that name.
I was young when I last spoke it to you.
And my face was as beautiful as my name.
And I loved you, Lyssa, with all my heart.
But you would not stay with me.
- There were responsibilities, duty...
- Ambition.
You had a son.
We had a son.
But you said nothing.
Where is he?
I killed him when he was born.
And this is my punishment.
My son?
Since I could not kill you,
my rage needed a victim.
I know you can never forgive me.
I cannot forgive myself.
I have already forgiven you.
You can never forgive a woman
who has killed your son.
If I had not...
could I see you now as I saw you then?
And allow me to see through your eyes.
How could I have left you?
Your vision is your gift to me.
And your vision could be your gift to me.
- What can I see for you?
- The Black Fortress, where does it rise?
Tomorrow...
in the Iron Desert.
But the knowledge is useless,
for you can't leave here.
No man has ever escaped the Web.
There is a young girl being held
in the Fortress.
A young girl with your name.
A young man seeks her.
The age I was when...
you and I met.
When you and I loved.
What you ask is beyond my power.
It can be turned only once.
That is the Law of the Web.
Then the second Lyssa will share your fate.
She will die, grow old and lonely.
She will die in a place of darkness.
This world will be a place of darkness.
These are the sands of my life.
Accept them and the spider
will have no power to harm you.
But your own life runs out with the sand.
What about your life?
I give it to the girl who bears my name.
I cannot stop the sand.
You cannot stop time.
Go now.
Save the other Lyssa.
At sunrise...
the Black Fortress will appear...
in the Iron Desert.
It will remain there until sunrise
of the following day.
You must...
You must reach it.
We'll reach it. You'll be with us.
No.
No, my...
race is run.
Use your power wisely.
Do not squander it.
I learned the power from you.
I won't forget.
We'll bury him here.
The Iron Desert's 1,000 leagues from here.
Fire mares.
Fire mares can travel
1,000 leagues in a day.
There's time if we move quickly.
That's it. Drive them back!
The grey is the leader!
Hold him!
Come on! Come on!
I've got you.
Gentle as a baby!
- Saddle the others, quickly!
- Right!
Come on. Hold still!
Stand still, you beast!
Take good care of him.
- Why doesn't he come?
- It's his time to die.
If he's going to die anyway,
why doesn't he come with us?
No. He must stay here and accept his fate.
If he opposes it,
he'll bring great pain on himself.
Steady! I must remain here.
Is it time?
You've done enough, Rell. Stay here.
Each to his fate.
Rell, I'll ride with you.
I have to stay here, my friend.
We had no time.
Hold on!
There it is!
Yes, and only madmen would want
to get this close to it.
We're going to get a lot closer.
And quickly. It's almost dawn.
We must get inside
before the twin suns rise.
Rhun, get back!
I was wrong.
The journey was worthwhile.
Finish it...
- We'll have to rush them.
- No, wait!
We'll be picked off as soon as we move.
Colwyn, look.
Follow him!
Come on!
Kegan! Mind the boy!
Get your axe in the opening!
It's no use.
This is my time.
Keep moving!
Which way?
Look out!
- My travelling days are over, my friend.
- We'll get you out of here.
Here's where I stay.
Lead on.
I can't hold him!
Throw us a rope!
Slayers!
I'm going down.
Go!
Get back!
- Come out!
- No, wait!
There is nothing we can do. Get out!
From here, I must go on alone.
Go where? There's no way in.
There is one way.
We must find the others, Ergo.
They've stopped.
Bardolph, let it go!
Look out!
'Lyssa! .Colwyn!
Not here, Colwyn. He's too powerful.
You must fight him away from the centre.
The Glaive is gone.
I have no way to fight him.
Colwyn, it's not the Glaive, it's you.
No, Lyssa, it's us.
It's us he can't defeat.
It won't return to me except from the hand
of the woman I choose as my wife.
I give it only to the man
whom I choose as my husband.
Take the fire from my hand.
We have to find the others. Come on!
I won't leave you, Ergo.
- Bardolph?
- Look, over here!
That's Ergo. He may still be alive.
Let's get out of here.
He risked his life to save us.
We can't leave him here
if there's even a chance he's alive.
Come on, let's get you out of here.
Stand back!
Help them down!
He'll be all right.
- You are his queen?
- Yes.
- Then we've won.
Oh, boy! I should have stuck to puppies!
I think...
it's time we unlocked those manacles.
I thought I'd keep them
as a memento of our journey.
The key's yours.
Only the king and his lord marshal
carry this key.
That's right.
A girl of ancient name shall become queen.
She shall choose a king,
and together they shall rule our world...
and their son shall rule the galaxy.